Stella Bay Los Altos CA 94024 707.321.6383 (cell) stella_bay@icloud.com

Psychotherapist

Expressive Arts * Harm Reduction * Emotional Regulation * Solution Focused

An authentic, compassionate, motivated mental health professional with more than 15 years' experience. Especially adept at helping clients heal emotional and psychological trauma. Extensive knowledge and experience with integrative psychotherapeutic methods such as DBT and Mindfulness. Excellent oral and written communication skills. Flexibility and ability to work both independently and as an active member of an interdisciplinary practice team. Ability to market self to grow referral base and recognition in the community. Effective care plan development and case manager.

Treatment Approach:

Person-Centered

Solution Focused

Transpersonal

Expressive Arts

Specialties:

Trauma & PTSD

Anxiety

Depression

Psychiatric Crisis

Professional Experience

Los Altos & Sausalito, California

Psychotherapist in Private Practice,

3/2016 - now

Build and maintain a caseload generating revenue to cover all operating costs. Perform all therapy within scope of practice. Assists patients in learning effective tools to cope and make healthy changes. Guide clients in the development of skills or strategies for emotional self-regulation. Develop and implement treatment plans based on clinical experience and knowledge that use objective goals. Maintain documentation congruent with managed care standards. Fill out and maintain client-related paperwork, including client diagnostic records, progress notes, and pre-authorizations of insurance. Collaborates with the other psychotherapists to implement and sustain best practices in the area of integrative psychotherapy; stays abreast of research and best practices in various fields.

- Provide comprehensive integrative assessment and counseling support.
- Assess and screen clients for depression, anxiety, insomnia, PTSD, traumatic brain injury, domestic violence, and suicidal ideation; and help them manage any severe symptoms.

- Offer deep listening, relaxation, mindful breathing, self-care coaching, coping skills, and symptom management techniques.
- Use art therapy to help clients manage symptoms, express feelings and regulate emotions.

Black Rock City NV & Washington D.C. Peer counselor & shift lead 8/28/2015 - now MAPS Zendo Project

Promote feelings of trust and security while sitting not guiding. Offer calm meditative presence, acceptance, compassion & caring. Talk through, don't resist challenging psychedelic experience. Create safe space, comfortable, warm, quiet, private, offer water & snacks. Difficult not bad: transform into opportunities for healing and growth.

San Francisco CA & Black Rock City NV Peer Counselor, 4/15/2015 - now

Burning Man Temple Guardians & People Operations.

Support internal human resource services, training, active listening, suicide prevention, culture of consent, coaching, counseling, mediation, conflict resolution, crisis intervention, personal well being, work/life balance stress relief.

Watch for injuries and unsafe conditions. Hold the sacred space of the temple. Invisible when not needed. Offering carrier when closed for burn.

Mental Health Professional, 1/2018 - 5/2018

Crisis Stabilization Unit (CSU) Nevada County & Sierra Mental Wellness Group - Grass Valley, CA

Acted independently and in conjunction with the CSU and Mental Health Evaluation Team (MHET)

to provide a variety of behavioral health services and referral support to clients residing in the

CSU. Prepared and maintained documentation related to client services to impact positive, healthy change in each client's life. Applied theories, principles and techniques of mental health treatment including clinical interviewing, assessment, diagnosis, crisis intervention, individual and group therapy and counseling. Identified psychological, physical and social aspects and characteristics of mental illness, emotional disturbances and chemical dependency while applying the applicable laws, rules, regulations and procedures governing mental health services, including 5150 protocols. Maintained knowledge of the principles, practices, procedures and operations of CSU programs, County and community mental health systems of care, community resources and related services, and basic psychiatric terminology and treatment methods, including uses, effects and side effects of psychotropic drugs, and an understanding and acceptance of the Wellness and Recovery Model.

Progress Foundation, San Francisco, California

Counselor / Relief Counselor / Case Manager, 8/2008 – 2/2016

Provided individual and group psychotherapy for patients with a focus on recovery principles. Supported the multidisciplinary treatment teams with assessment, consultation, and milieu therapy (as a context for realistic assessment and diagnosis of a patient's level of functioning and interpersonal capabilities). Promoted social rehabilitation by giving patients responsibility for driving their own stabilization process. Assisted patients in the development and improvement of interpersonal skills.

- Provided psychiatric emergency counseling, psychiatric crisis stabilization, and social rehabilitation.
- Orchestrated social and relational aspects of treatment environment to encourage group cohesion.
- Built relationships with patients with a strong peer quality, empathy, genuineness, and compassion.
- Administered the most effective, evidence based, and efficient case management services.

•

Youth Spirit Artworks, Berkeley, California Expressive Arts Therapist, 3/2008 – 2/2012

Conducted individual and group psychotherapy for at-risk and homeless teens utilizing the expressive arts in order to treat, assess, and provide diagnostic impressions for patients. Maintained appropriate plans, progress notes, and evaluative program reports. Offered encouraging career counseling.

- Transformed the lives of homeless and at-risk teens, using art jobs and training for their empowerment.
- Developed and implemented an interfaith expressive arts curriculum to give youth the skills, experience, and self-confidence to reach their full potential.
- Modeled and taught youthful art skills including installations of public murals and ceramic tile mosaics; and up cycling furniture with art using paint, stencils, air brush, ceramic tile, and mixed media.
- Created opportunities for the youth to sell their art and earn money.

Additional Experience:

Art Therapist, at Genuine DBT, Chico, CA

Hospice Caregiver, at Sequoia Senior Solutions, Petaluma, CA

Domestic Violence & Sexual Assault Counselor, at Casa de Esperanza de Los Ninos, Yuba City, CA

Agency Liaison, at A Window Between Worlds, Venice, CA

MFT Trainee, at Stand! For Families Free of Violence, Concord, CA

Youth Counselor, at Huckleberry Youth Programs, San Anselmo, CA

Grief Counselor, at Family Service Agency, San Rafael, CA

Education and Credentials

Master of Arts in Counseling Psychology – Expressive Arts Therapy (2004)

California Institute of Integral Studies, San Francisco, CA

Bachelor of Arts in Psychology

University of Missouri, Columbia, MO

Licensure

Marriage and Family Therapist (MFT) in California

Professional Development

<u>Dialectical Behavior Therapy: Treatment for Borderline Personality Disorder,</u> Zur Institute

<u>Person Centered Expressive Arts Therapy Institute</u>, Sonoma State University, Rohnert Park, CA

Expressive Arts Therapy and Mindfulness, Naropa University, Boulder, CO